LAUREN DUKER DARRIMON

Sonoma County, CA | +1 (707) 243 3038 | <u>laurendarrimon@gmail.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/lauren-duker-darrimon</u> | <u>github.com/LaurenDarrimon</u> | <u>laurendarrimon.github.io/portfolio</u>

SUMMARY

Full-stack Engineer with experience in UI design, graphic design, and managing freelance projects. Skills in JavaScript, React.js, databases, MVC architecture, and MERN stack. Skilled logical reasoner who loves analytical problem-solving. Strong verbal communicator who excels in writing readable, well-documented code. Aims to leverage background in UI to architect an inspiring experience, for both the front end and back end.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development, 2022
University of California Berkeley, Extension - Berkeley, CA
Certificate Mobile & Front End Development, 2021
Santa Rosa Junior College - Santa Rosa, CA
Bachelor of Science in Engineering Physics, incomplete, 2002 - 2007
Colorado School of Mines - Golden, CO

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Full-stack web developer, skilled in problem-solving, JavaScript, OOP, declarative and imperative programming, MVC architecture, Git, version control, and the MERN stack
- Front End development including React.js, Vue.js, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Foundation, and JQuery
- Databases including relational, SQL, Sequelize, and IndexDB, and non-relational, Mongo DB, Mongoose
- Back End and server development with Command-Line, Node.js, Express.js, REST API, Apollo GraphQL
- UI/UX design, graphic design for digital and print, including Adobe Creative Suite, WordPress, & Figma
- Skilled in logical troubleshooting, both in broad system-level thinking and attention to small details

PROJECTS

GIT MATCH | github.com/LaurenDarrimon/git-match | morning-sea-85016.herokuapp.com

- Full Stack MERN social network application for new developers to find collaboration, community, and groups
- Built UI, managed React state, configured type definitions, resolvers, queries & mutations, designed logo
- Utilized React.js, Apollo GraphQL, MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, and GitHub API

NEIGHBORGOOD! | github.com/LaurenDarrimon/community-share | hidden-forest-09542.herokuapp.com

- Full Stack free-cycling application where users log in to post items and claim used items offered by others
- Engineered REST API routes to update a relational database. Built server-side templating and cloud-based storage
- Employed MVC architecture, Handlebars.js template engine, MySQL, Sequelize, Express.js, and Express Session

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE WEB DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT, 2019 - present

- Executes entire lifecycle from ideation through the deployment of mobile-first websites for small businesses
- Develops APIs for digital marketing integrations and analytics, increasing revenue & retention
- Creates unique brand identity and designs original logos, labels, and brand assets in digital and print formats

CLIENTS, OPERATIONS & WEB DESIGN 01/2019 - 11/2021 Euphoria Retreats, Sonoma, CA

- Launched two company rebrands. Team designed/developed new websites as the business adapted to COVID
- Implemented digital marketing overhaul with API integrations, Hubspot, Zoho, and reservation software
- Ran client communications, booking, and travel operations for 8-10+ successful international retreats per year